Ian Ames - CV

Profile

I help multidisciplinary teams deliver services in a user centred way.

I have delivered projects to a range of Government organisations including the Cabinet Office, Dept for Culture Media and Sport, NHS Digital, Ministry of Justice and TechUK.

At Land Registry I delivered their first user-centred Digital services meeting the <u>Service Standard</u>, as well as internal projects for 4000 distributed staff.

I have experience of a number of agile ways of working such as Scrum, Kanban, Cynefin, Lean and DevOps.

I have experience of leading co-located, distributed and fully remote teams. Clear communication and a shared understanding of goals is key, regardless of where your team is. I work hard to ensure teams are pulling in the same direction and are focused on the project outcomes.

I have spoken at meetups for Agile Southwest, Product Makers, Citizens Advice and Co-Op digital communities, and have presented at the FutureSync, <u>TechExeter</u>, and <u>Agile on the Beach</u> conferences. I have also helped facilitate the excellent <u>Agile in the Ether</u> and <u>Product in the (A)ether</u> meetups and conference.

Career

Ministry of Justice/DXW

Contract Delivery Manager, December 2022 to present

Working with dxw to deliver an discovery/alpha for Ministry of Justice. Working closely with Product Manager to understand stakeholder needs. Supporting, enabling and advocating for User Reasearch to ensure we understand the end user perspective. Coordrinating with other delivery managers at MOJ and sharing good practices. Identifying team improvements to ways of working and team health and happiness. Liasing with Delivery Lead to forecast team shape and spend.

NHS Digital

Contract Product Manager, June 2022 to December 2022

Working with stakeholders and commissioners to understand strategy intent and goals. Understanding user needs to ensure our product meets them. Setting team priorities and ensuring value is delivered. Being the 'voice of the product' to the wider organisation.

Contract Delivery Manager, April 2021 - June 2022

Responsible for the delivery of designated products and services by one or more multi-disciplinary user-centred or software delivery teams.

Delt Shared Services

Innovation Specialist, September 2020 to April 2021.

Responsible for developing innovation at Delt, understanding our customers issues and challenges and exploring emerging technology and products to present and test solutions in a user centred and iterative way.

Surevine

Technical Team Lead, May 2019 to August 2020.

Responsible for developing a high performing remote team of software developers and testers, delivering customer projects and developing our working practices for efficent and effective agile software delivery.

HM Land Registry

Delivery Lead, 2014 - 2019.

I led a multidisciplinary team to develop the <u>Find Property Information service</u>. in a user-centric way using agile techniques based on the <u>Government Service Design Manual</u>. My team successfully passed the beta assessment of the <u>Government Digital Service Standard</u>. I advocated and acted as the voice of agile practice to the rest of the organisation.

New Services Manager, 2011 - 2014.

I acted as primary liaison between development and operations department to ensure a smooth transition of services to production. I was Subject Matter Expert for cross functional requirements on projects. I developed support process and change controls for services transitioning to production.

Senior Change Analyst, 2009 - 2011.

Configuration Analyst, 2007 - 2009.

Infrastructure Support Engineer, 2004 - 2007

Vospers

Contract Systems Administrator, 2004

TWR/Menard Engineering

Systems Administrator, 2001 - 2003

Projects

Refer and Monitor and accredited Programme - 2023

Leading a discovery/alpha into the identification, referal and monitoring of accredited programmes in custody. Accredited programmes are behavioural programmes designed to give people in prisoners the tools they need to reintegrate with society and reduce reoffending.

NHS Urgent and Emergency Care Directory of Services (DoS) integration team - 2022

Product Managed the directory of services integration team who were respeonsible for retriving information from other data sources such as NHS.UK to ensure the DoS was as up to date as possible. Managed multiple competing priorities and worked with the team to provide clear guidance on what to work on next. Nurtured a culture of continuous delivery and experimentation to increase our delivery rate. Worked with stakeholders to provide a vision of how the tem could deliver relevant information regardles of dta source, reducing the need for data duplication, balanced against stringent performance requirmeents for data in urgent care settings.

Patient Encounter History - 2021-22

Led the development of a product to enable clincians from different parts of Urgent and Emergency Care to view information about patient encounters in other care settings in order to help diagnose complex cases, reassure patients and build rapport, and to identify worsening conditions. This was developed in a user centred way using Discovery to understand patient and clincial needs and Alpha to iteratively prototype and explore technical options.

GPintheCloud, 2020 - 21

Led the development of a product to enable GP Locums to access clinical systems for multiple surgeries from one device securely. The service was developed based on user feedback and enabled Locums to support GP surgeries from anywhere in the country, crucial during the coronavirus pandemic, but a solution to the challenge of GP distribution across the country.

Cyber Exchange, 2020

Project Lead for the delivery of Cyber-Exchange, a platform for UK Cyber Security businesses to connect, find funding opportunities and events . Sponsored by DCMS and Tech UK.

Future Vetting Service, 2019

Project lead for the delivery of serverless future vetting website on AWS, with cross domain aspects on Docker Swarm, working closely with the NCSC and the Cabinet Office, leading a multi-disciplinary team of User Researchers, Designers,

Developers, and Testers and supporting and coaching the teams Product Managers in Agile ways of working.

Protect Alpha, 2018

A citizen focused service to allow citizens to easily protect their property interests. Keep their information on the register up to date, and to raise awareness of what Land Registry is and how we protect most people's largest asset, their home.

Find Property Information, 2016 - 17

A citizen focused service aimed at presenting basic land information for a number of user needs. Built on an entirely new infrastructure stack, including accounts, payment, audit, address API's. Migrated 24 million titles of land ownership data to a new database platform. Developed our emerging agile practices and increased our deployment frequency from once a month to on-demand, completing 76 production deploys in 2017.

Network transformation, 2015

Led the design and procurement of new multi-zoned and geographically dispersed network to support and protect over 70 land registry services, and the land register, part of the critical national infrastrucre.

Laptop Refresh, 2014

Delivered new laptops to 500 remote users, distributed throughout the country, along with a new remote working solution which simplified and expanded access to corporate services remotely. All within the time/cost/quality specs of the project.

Support Forum, 2013

Delivered a support forum/twitter feed, corresponding processes and training to provide users with the ability to search for solutions, report issues, ideas, or praise and allow Land Registry to gain valuable customer insight.

iPad and BYOD solution, 2013.

Rapid delivery of iPads to senior leaders and a corresponding system to access corporate information securely within 6 weeks, this enabled BYOD capabilities for HM Land Registry.

Education and Training

Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance 2015.

BSc (Hons) Marine Navigation. University of Plymouth, 1998 - 2001.

ITIL Practitioner in:

- Foundation
- Service Design
- Service Transition
- Service Desk and Incident Management
- Service Level Management

I have previously been SC cleared. I have BPSS clearance.

Contact Details

ian@discover-deliver.co.uk

07939340716

https://ames.world

LinkedIn

71 Somerset Place, Stoke, Plymouth, PL3 4BQ